Birendra Kr. Sharma

(MERN Stack Developer)

+91-9709857928 kumarbeeru.kbs@gmail.com kumarbeeru.github.io linkedin.com/in/birendrakumarshrma

Bhagalpur, 813105 (BR)

gitlab.com/rajbeeru675

Profile Summary

I have around six years of experience in the IT Industry, in which 1+ years of relevant experience in Node.Js, 2+ years in React JS, and 5+ years with Laravel, and all phases of Project development like Designing, Development, Testing, Deployment, and Documentations. I describe myself as - Innovating, Executing, Collaborating, and Having Fun! I'm here to turn your ideas into reality. My strong points are my Responsibility and Punctuality.

Key Skills

NodeJS(Skillful), React.JS(Skillful), Laravel(Experienced), PHP, ES6, REST API(Experienced, GIT, SQL, MySQL(Skillful), Mongo, Swagger, Apache, Nginx, Digital Ocean, AWS, Shopify,

Work Experience

Software Developer

Company: Marmeto, Url: marmeto.com, Bengaluru, Karnataka

11/2021 - Present

- Shopify Public App using Laravel, Node and React Js
- Woo-commerce Plugin: Php
- Shopify Payment Getway Node, React and MySql

Software Developer

Company: Web Revolution, Url: webrevolution.in, Ahmadabad, Gujarat 12/2019 – 11/2021

- Modified HTML, CSS, Laravel, and Javascript Code to optimize the page performance for faster loading and browsing.
- Developed APIs of crypto wallet system using Laravel and MySql and integrated swagger for api documentation as a back-end developer.
- Designed and developed the project using React.js(Redux), Laravel, and MySql.
- Designed and developed the admin panel of Shopify custom application using Laravel and MySql.
- Updated the Mobile Application's feature and optimized the React Native(Redux) code to fulfill the client's requirements.
- Designed and developed the Telegram bots using laravel and python.
- Developed the desktop application using python.
- Wrote script for the crypto trading in python and MS-Excel.

Financial Service Consultant

Company: ICICI Prudential Life Insurance, Url: iciciprulife.com, Bhagalpur, Bihar 06/2019 – 11/2019

• Explaining the benefits of the insurance, saving, and investment and convince them to buy.

Full-Stack Developer

Freelancer (During My College)

11/2016 - .03/2019

- Understand the requirements of the client and fulfilled them.
- Coordinated with the team and managed the complete life cycle of the project development.
- Developed many projects using Laravel, HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JS, Jquery, React Native, Expo, and MySql.

Education

BCA (Bachelor in Computer Applications) (Aug 2018 with 71%)

→ T. N. B College Bhagalpur, Bihar

Language

Hindi, English

Project Summary

- 1. Easy Parcel Shopify Shipping App:
 - Url: https://apps.shopify.com/easyparcel-delivery-made-easy
 - Language and Tools: Laravel, React and Mysql
 - Role: Full Stack Developer
 - Responsibilities: Database Design, Frontend Development and Api Development
- 2. Project Snapbots Wallet (Crypto Wallet)
 - Url: https://app.snapbots.io/#/pages/login
 - Language and Tools: Laravel, Angular, MySql, Swagger, Sentry
 - Role: Back-end Developer
 - Responsibilities: Designed the database and Developed the Apis.
- 3. Project: Online Test App
 - Language and tools: ES6, CSS, React Native, Expo, Laravel.
 - Database: MySql
 - Url: http://hardigurdi.com
 - Role and responsibility:
 - Understand the client's requirements.
 - Researched the requirements and distributed the modules among the team.
 - Designed the database and front-end and back-end for the test section.